CRISTIAN WILGENHOFF

Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer specialised in JavaScript.

Summary

Having worked in the Tech industry for 6 years for companies such as Microsoft, Deloitte, US Bank, Best Buy and Bally Technologies and several startups, I aim to bring diverse experience and add fruitful value in a role where I can take real software development ownership.

I prefer to work on real and exciting products with active clients, with a driven team that I can add to and learn from.

• Name: Cristian Wilgenhoff

Location: London, UK

E-mail: cpwilgenhoff@gmail.com

Website: http://cwilgenhoff.github.io/
 Github: https://github.com/cwilgenhoff

• **Phone:** 07493 074226

FarmDrop, Full-Stack Engineer

March 2016 - Current

Employment

Information

- Part of the customer facing team in charge of building a marketplace for locally sourced food.
- Tasks include adding features fast, migrating legacy Angular components into React, major rebranding of the shop and the continuous improvement of the current code base through the introduction of best practices such as a testing infrastructure for the front-end components using Enzyme.
- **Technologies**: JS (ES6), React, Redux, Webpack, Jest, Enzyme, Ruby on Rails, Redis.

Contentment, Full-Stack Engineer

Nov 2015 – Feb 2016

- Part of the development team in charge of building the "Reader App", a Cordova application built
 entirely in React acting as a proxy for downloading assets from the cloud (publications).
- Tasks included designing the structure of the app from scratch, providing a way to load content dynamically and testing on real devices.
- Technologies: JS (ES6), React, RxJS, PouchDB, NodeJS.

Making Sense LLC, Full-Stack Engineer

May 2014 - Nov 2015

- Project: Budget Maestro Contractor for Centage Full-Stack Engineer
 - o Part of the development team in charge of building Budget Maestro, an application that provides budgeting solutions for companies.
 - Tasks included re-structuring front-end architecture, integrating with Bower package manager, rapid development of new features for the business logic, creation of unit testing and E2E tests, and standardisation of the code style.
 - o The application connects to a backend designed and developed in Spring/Java.
 - $\circ \quad \hbox{ Discussions with stakeholders for feedback and feature enhancement.}$
 - Technologies: AngularJS, MongoDB.
- Project: BCP Contractor for Mobiquity, Inc Full-Stack Engineer
 - Responsible and part of the development team of a product for the Healthcare industry named BCP (Behavior Change Platform).
 - o This product was aimed to help users change their behaviors according to a set of objectives through follow up.
 - Part of an agile environment using two week sprints.
 - O Developed integrations against the Twilio API, Fitbit API, AWS and proprietary third party API.
 - o Developed unit tests in MochaJS and SinonJS for BE and Karma with Jasmine for FE.
 - o **Technologies**: *NodeJS, Angular, MongoDB, Express.*

2012 - 2013

- Project: Migration of Desktop App Contractor for EasySoft USA Frontend Engineer
 - o **Technologies**: Dojo Toolkit, JavaScript
- Project: Best Buy Store Contractor for migration.mobi Software Engineer
 - o Technologies: Windows Phone 8, Windows 8 Metro, XAML
- Project: Cash+ Visa Card Contractor for migration.mobi Software Engineer
 - Technologies: Windows Phone 7, XAML

Globant, Software Engineer

2011 - 2014

- Project: RGS Contractor for Bally Technologies Deployment Engineer
 - o Part of the development team in charge of creating scripts for automatic deployments.
 - o **Technologies**: PowerShell
- Project: TV Chip Recognition Contractor for Bally Technologies Software Engineer
 - o Technologies: .NET, C# 4.0, WPF, WCF
- Project: Internal Intranet Contractor for Deloitte SharePoint Developer
 - o Technologies: .NET, C# 4.0, SharePoint 2010

Glafon S.A. (Southworks), SharePoint Developer

2010 - 2011

- Project: PDC 2010 (Deployment) Contractor for Microsoft SharePoint Developer
 - o **Technologies**: SharePoint 2010, PowerShell, TeamCity.
- Project: KEXP (CMS for Streams) Contractor for KEXP Radio SharePoint Developer
 - o **Technologies:** SharePoint 2010

PandemSim – Contractor for University of Ohio - Full-Stack Engineer

Feb 2015 – April 2015

Freelance

- During the first quarter of 2015, I worked as a contractor for the University of Ohio. Our goal was to create a platform for students to perform controlled simulations of different diseases around the world. The main consumers were college students and professors.
- Technology: NodeJS, AngularJS, Express, MongoDB and Socket.IO.

• Languages: JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS

- Libraries/APIs: Async, RxJS, React, Redux, React Router, Three.js
- Frameworks: NodeJS, Express, Socket.IO, Angular, Twitter Bootstrap
- Testing Tools: Karma, MochaJS, Chai, SinonJS, Jasmine, Protractor, Jest, Enzyme
- JS Code Style Checkers: JSHint, JSCS, ESHint
- **DB/Storage:** PouchDB, CouchDB, MongoDB
- Cl and Automation Tools: Heroku, Jenkins, Travis, Teamcity, Grunt, Gulp

2006 - 2014

Education

Skills

Systems Engineering

National University of Central Buenos Aires (UNICEN) - Buenos Aires

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Spanish (Native)